Register of the Tom Mboya papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Trade Unions Series, 1950-1968
  - Trade Unions and Their Constitutions (T/1). Constitutions, memoranda, press release, and regulations, 1957-1959
    Box/Folder 16: 5
  - Union Affairs (T/2). Correspondence, press release, receipts, reports, speech, and serial issue, 1958-1968
    - Nos. 1-50
      Box/Folder 16: 6
    - Nos. 51-82 (Reel 19)
      Box/Folder 16: 7. Includes printed copy of an article by Tom Mboya, "Trade Unions and Development," Venture, 1964 January, and typescript of a speech by Tom Mboya, 1967 May 21
  - General Correspondence (T/5). Bulletins, correspondence, minutes of meetings, and reports. Includes correspondence relating to the International Confederation of Free Trade Unions (ICFTU)
    - 1959-1963
      Box/Folder 17: 1
    - 1964
      Box/Folder 17: 2
    - 1965-1966
      Box/Folder 17: 3
  - Trade Union Meetings (T/4). Application forms, correspondence, memoranda, notices, reports, and statements
    - 1950-1955 (Reel 20)
      Box/Folder 17: 4
    - 1956-1968
      Box/Folder 17: 5. Includes typescript of an unpublished letter by Tom Mboya to the editor of the New York Times, 1958 May 5
  - Trade Dispute - Mombassa/Kilindini Port (T/5). Memoranda and minutes of meetings, 1955
    Box/Folder 17: 6
  - Trade Dispute - Nairobi City Council (T/6). Clippings, correspondence, report, and transcript of proceedings, 1954-1956
    Box/Folder 18: 1
  - Wages Advisory Board (T/7). Agendas, correspondence, minutes of meetings, notes, and reports, 1955-1956
    Box/Folder 18: 2
  - Labor Advisory Board (T/8). Agenda, correspondence, memorandum, minutes of meeting, and reports, 1960
    Box/Folder 18: 3
  - Correspondence with Foreign Organizations. Bulletins, clippings, correspondence, serial issues, and reports.
    Includes letters exchanged between Tom Mboya and Irving Brown, Jay Lovestone, A. Philip Randolph, Victor Reuther, Walter Reuther, and Maida Springer
    - Volume one (T/9/v.1)
      - 1956-1958
        Box/Folder 18: 4
      - 1959-1960 (Reel 21)
        Box/Folder 18: 5
    - Volume two (T/9/v.2)
      - 1961
        - March-July
          Box/Folder 18: 6
        - August-December
          Box/Folder 19: 1
      - 1962
        Box/Folder 19: 2
    - Volume three, (T/9/v.3), 1964-1968
      Box/Folder 19: 3
  - U.S.A. - General (T/10). Clipping, correspondence, and serial issue, 1960-1962 (Reel 22)
    Box/Folder 19: 4. Includes letters exchanged between Tom Mboya and Jay B. Krane, Jay Lovestone, George Meany, Victor Reuther, and Maida Springer
  - American Federation of Labor (T/11). Clippings, correspondence, press releases, and statements, 1962-1968
    Box/Folder 19: 5. Includes letters exchanged between Tom Mboya and Irving Brown, Jay Lovestone, George Meany, and Maida Springer
  - International Confederation of Free Trade Unions (ICFTU) - Correspondence (T/12). Clipping, correspondence, minutes of meetings, reports, and statements. Includes letters exchanged between Tom Mboya and Jay B. Krane, David Newman, and J. H. Oldenbroek
    - 1956-1958
      Box/Folder 19: 6
    - 1959-1960
      Box/Folder 19: 7. Includes typescript of a statement by Tom Mboya, 1959 May(?)
  - ICFTU - East, Central, and Southern Africa Area Committee Meeting, (T/13)., 1961
    Box/Folder 20: 1. Agenda, circular, minutes of meeting, and reports, 1961
  - ICFTU - Sixth World Congress (T/14). Correspondence, invitation, resolution, and statement, 1959-1962
    Box/Folder 20: 2
  - ICFTU - Nairobi Meeting, 1962 (T/15). Correspondence, minutes of meeting, and rules, 1961-1962
    Box/Folder 20: 3
  - ICFTU - Arusha Conference, (T/16)., 1958
    Box/Folder 20: 4. Correspondence, report, and statements, 1957-1958
  - ICFTU - Third African Regional Conference, Tunis, (T/17)., 1960 (Reel 23)
    Box/Folder 20: 5. Agenda, reports, rules, speeches, 1960
  - Kenya Federation of Labor (KFL) - Annual Conference, (T/18)., 1960
    Box/Folder 20: 6. Constitution, correspondence, list of delegates, reports, and policy statement by Tom Mboya, 1960
  - Kenya Federation of Labor (KFL) - Press Statement (T/19). Press release, 1960
    Box/Folder 20: 7
  - ICFTU - African Regional Conference, Lagos, Nigeria, (T/20)., 1959-1961
    Box/Folder 20: 8. Correspondence, lists of delegates, minutes of meetings, notes, reports, and speeches, 1959-1960. Includes text of a speech by Tom Mboya, 1959 November(?)
  - ICFTU - Minutes and Reports (T/21). Agendas, bulletins, correspondence, minutes of meetings, press release, and reports, 1960-1962
    Box/Folder 20: 9
  - Kenya Federation of Labor (KFL) - General Correspondence. Correspondence, memoranda, minutes of meetings, press releases, receipts, reports, and speeches
    - Volume one, (KFL/1/v.1), 1958-1963 (Reel 24)
      Box/Folder 21: 1
    - Volume two (KFl/1/v.2)
      - 1956-1957
        Box/Folder 21: 2
      - 1958
        Box/Folder 21: 3
    - Volume three, (KFL1/1/v.3), 1962-1964
      - Nos. 1-100
        Box/Folder 21: 4
      - Nos. 101-176 (Reel 25)
        Box/Folder 21: 5
    - Volume four (KFL/1/v.4)
      - 1959-1960
        Box/Folder 21: 6
      - 1961
        - January-June
          Box/Folder 22: 1
        - July-December
          Box/Folder 22: 2
    - Volume five (KFl/1/v.5)
      - 1961
        Box/Folder 22: 3. Includes typescript of a speech by Tom Mboya, 1961(?)
      - 1962
        Box/Folder 22: 4
      - 1963-1964 (Reel 26)
        Box/Folder 22: 5
- Seminars and Conferences Series, 1961-1969
  Address, conference papers, correspondence, invitations, list, minutes of meetings, printed matter, programs, notes, reports, resolution, seminar papers, serial issue, speeches, and statements, largely relating to Tom Mboya's activities as Kenyan Minister for Economic Planning and Development, arranged by conference name or subject in numerical sequence according to original file numbers
  - United Nations Economic Commission for Africa (CS/1). Correspondence, proposals, reports, and statements, 1965
    Box/Folder 22: 6
  - International Conference on Economic Sanctions against South Africa, 1964. Program, notes, reports, and speeches
    - Volume one (CS/2/v.1)
      Box/Folder 22: 7
    - Volume two (CS/2/v.2)
      Box/Folder 23: 1
    - Volume two (CS/2/v.2) (cont.) (Reel 27)
      Box/Folder 23: 2
  - Conference on Tensions in Development in the Western Hemisphere, 1962 (CS/3). Correspondence, invitations, list of participants, reports, serial issue, and speeches, 1961-1962
    Box/Folder 23: 3. Includes correspondence unrelated to conference
  - Conference on World Cooperation for Development, 1968 (CS/4). Conference papers and correspondence
    Box/Folder 23: 4
  - Economic Commission for Africa, Seventh Session, 1965 (CS/5/1). List of participants and conference statement
    Box/Folder 23: 5
  - Seminars and Conferences - General Correspondence (CS/5). Correspondence, printed matter, programs, and speeches, 1961-1966
    Box/Folder 23: 6
  - Organization of African Unity - Conferences and Resolutions (CS/6). Correspondence, reports, resolution, and speech by Jomo Kenyatta, 1964 (Reel 28)
    Box/Folder 24: 1
  - United Nations - General Correspondence. Correspondence and reports
    - Volume one, (CS/7/v.1), 1964-1969
      Box/Folder 24: 2
    - Volume two, (CS/7/v.2)., 1964-1969
      Box/Folder 24: 3. Includes letters exchanged between Tom Mboya and Burudi Nabwera
  - Seminar on Community Development in East Africa, 1965 (CS/8). List of participants, program, and seminar papers
    Box/Folder 24: 4
  - Kenya Women's Seminar, 1962 (CS/9). Correspondence, minutes of meetings, and speeches, 1962-1963
    Box/Folder 24: 5
  - Commonwealth Parliamentary Association (CS/10). Correspondence, membership lists, and minutes of meetings, 1961-1963
    Box/Folder 24: 6
  - Kenya Coastal Strip Conference, 1962 (CS/11). Memoranda, minutes of meetings, press releases, report, and statement by Jomo Kenyatta
    Box/Folder 24: 7
  - Seminar on Racial and Communal Tensions in East Africa, 1964 (CS/12). Opening address, seminar papers, and concluding statement
    Box/Folder 24: 8
- General Correspondence with Foreign Countries Series, 1958-1969
  Clippings, correspondence, minutes of meetings, press releases, statements, and reports, largely relating to speaking engagements by Tom Mboya and issues involving the overseas education of Kenyan students, arranged by name of country or continent in numerical sequence according to original file numbers
  Correspondence and other materials, listed by country of residence of correspondent, and consisting primarily of letters addressed to or written by Tom Mboya, including many referring to speaking engagements by Tom Mboya or to Kenyan students studying abroad
  - Correspondence with the United States of America
    - Volume one (FOR/1/v.1)
      - 1959
        - February-May (Reel 25)
          Box/Folder 25: 1
        - June-July
          Box/Folder 25: 2
        - August-October
          Box/Folder 25: 3
        - November-December
          Box/Folder 25: 4
      - 1960
        - January-February
          Box/Folder 25: 5
        - March-April
          Box/Folder 25: 6
    - Volume two, (FOR/1/v.2), 1962-1968 (Reel 30)
      Box/Folder 26: 1
    - Volume three, (FOR/1/v.3), 1968-1969
      Box/Folder 26: 2
    - Volume four, (FOR/1/v.4), 1958-1963
      Box/Folder 26: 3
  - Correspondence with Canada (FOR/2)
    - 1960
      Box/Folder 26: 4
    - 1961
      - January-June
        Box/Folder 26: 5
      - July-December
        Box/Folder 26: 6
    - 1962 (Reel 31)
      Box/Folder 26: 7
  - Correspondence with Belgium (FOR/3). Clippings, correspondence, minutes of meetings, press releases, statements, and reports, largely relating to the International Confederation of Free Trade Unions (ICFTU) and its member organizations
    - 1960
      Box/Folder 27: 1
    - 1961
      Box/Folder 27: 2
    - 1962-1963
      Box/Folder 27: 3
  - Correspondence with European Countries - General (FOR/4).
    Includes some correspondence relating to the ICFTU and its member organizations
    - 1960
      Box/Folder 27: 4
    - 1961
      Box/Folder 27: 5
    - 1962-1964 (Reel 32)
      Box/Folder 27: 6
  - Correspondence with the Republic of China, (FOR/5), 1962-1963
    Box/Folder 27: 7
  - Correspondence with Ceylon, (FOR/6), 1962
    Box/Folder 27: 8
  - Correspondence with Jamaica, (FOR/7), 1962-1963
    Box/Folder 27: 9
  - Correspondence with Singapore, (FOR/8), 1963
    Box/Folder 27: 10
  - Correspondence with Bermuda, (FOR/9), 1965-1966
    Box/Folder 27: 11
- Foreign Embassies and Representatives Series, 1957-1969
  Aide-mémoire, correspondence, invitations, itinerary, memorandum, minutes of meetings, serial issue, speech, and student records, largely relating to Tom Mboya's activities as Kenyan Minister for Economic Planning and Development, arranged by name of diplomatic mission or continent in numerical sequence according to original file numbers
  - Japanese Embassy in Kenya (DIP/1). Aide-mémoire, correspondence, invitations, and itinerary, 1964-1969
    Box/Folder 28: 1
  - Kenyan Embassy in the Soviet Union (DIP/2). Correspondence, 1964-1968
    Box/Folder 28: 2
  - South America (DIP/3). Correspondence, largely relating to official visits by Tom Mboya to Barbados and Venezuela, 1966-1967
    Box/Folder 28: 3
  - Commission for India (DIP/4). Correspondence, minutes of meetings, serial issue, student records, and reports, 1957-1960
    Box/Folder 28: 4
  - Israeli Embassy in Kenya. Correspondence, itinerary, memorandum of agreement, reports, and speech
    - Volume one, (DIP/5/v.1)., 1962-1969
      Box/Folder 28: 5. Includes correspondence with Golda Meir and Shimon Peres, and typescript of a speech made by Tom Mboya in Jerusalem, 1962 January 29
    - Volume two, (DIP/5/v.2), 1962
      Box/Folder 28: 6
  - Swedish Embassy in Kenya (DIP/6). Correspondence, 1964-1968
    Box/Folder 28: 7
  - Finnish Consulate in Kenya (DIP/7). Correspondence, 1962-1965
    Box/Folder 28: 8
- Public Affairs Series, 1951-1969
  Applications, architectural plans, articles, briefing papers, clippings, correspondence, invitations, press releases, receipts, reports, transcripts, serial issues, and speeches, largely relating to Tom Mboya's activities as Kenyan Minister for Economic Planning and Development, and as Secretary General of the Kenya Federation of Labor, arranged by subject or physical form in numerical sequence according to original file numbers
  - Art and Culture. Architectural plans, clipping, correspondence, press releases, and reports
    - Volume one, (AC/1/v.1), 1964-1966 (Reel 33)
      Box/Folder 28: 9
    - Volume two, (AC/1/v.2), 1966-1969
      Box/Folder 28: 10
  - Kenya Gazette (KG/1). Printed copies of government records, 1963-1967
    Box/Folder 28: 11
  - Press Statements. Article, briefing papers, clippings, correspondence, official Kenya News Agency reports, press releases, program transcripts, serial issues, and speeches, including many by Tom Mboya
    - Volume one, (PS/1), 1963-1967 (Reel 34)
      Box/Folder 29: 1
    - Volume two, (PS/2), 1964-1967
      Box/Folder 29: 2
    - Volume three
      - Part one, (PS/3/v.1), 1962-1966
        Box/Folder 29: 3
      - Part two, (PS/3/v.2), 1964-1966
        Box/Folder 29: 4
    - Volume four, (PS/4), 1968
      Box/Folder 29: 5
    - Volume five, (PS/5), 1964-1965
      Box/Folder 29: 6
    - Volume six, (PS/6)., 1969 (Reel 35)
      Box/Folder 30: 1. Includes typescript drafts of an article written by Tom Mboya for Ebony, undated.
    - Volume seven, (PS/7)., 1969
      Box/Folder 30: 2. Includes transcripts of radio and television interviews with Tom Mboya, 1969
  - Speeches and Invitations.
    Correspondence, invitations, serial issues, and speeches by Tom Mboya
    - Volume one, (PS/9/v.1), 1966-1967
      - Nos. 1-100
        Box/Folder 30: 3
      - Nos. 101-149
        Box/Folder 30: 4
    - Volume two, (PS/9/v.2), 1965-1966
      Box/Folder 30: 5
  - Newspaper Articles. Correspondence and clippings of newspaper articles, including many by or about Tom Mboya
    - Volume one (PS/10)
      - 1959-1965
        Box/Folder 30: 6
      - 1966 (Reel 36)
        Box/Folder 31: 1
      - 1967
        Box/Folder 31: 2
    - Volume two (PS/11)
      - 1951-1956
        Box/Folder 31: 3
      - 1957
        - January-June
          Box/Folder 31: 4
        - July-December
          Box/Folder 31: 5
      - 1958
        Box/Folder 31: 6
  - Programs and Clippings (PS/12). Correspondence, clippings of newspaper articles about Tom Mboya, and programs, 1960-1969
    Box/Folder 31: 7
  - Public Meetings (PS/13). Applications, correspondence, and receipts, 1957-1966
    Box/Folder 31: 8
- Development Plans Series, 1964-1969
  Briefing papers, correspondence, digests, memoranda, minutes of meetings, press releases, programs, proposals, receipts, and reports, largely relating to Tom Mboya's activities as Kenyan Minister for Economic Planning and Development, arranged by physical form or subject in numerical sequence according to original file numbers
  - Quarterly Economic Report and Kenya Statistical Digest (DP/1). Correspondence, digests, press releases, and reports
    - 1965-1966
      Box/Folder 31: 9
    - 1967-1969 (Reel 37)
      Box/Folder 32: 1
  - Quarterly Economic Report - Daily Letter File (DLF). Correspondence and press releases, 1968-1969
    Box/Folder 32: 2
  - Manpower Survey (DP/2). Report, 1965
    Box/Folder 32: 3
  - Provincial Plan for Schools (DP/3). Correspondence and minutes of meetings, 1967-1968
    Box/Folder 32: 4
  - Development Plan - Road Construction and Maintenance (DP/4). Memoranda and proposals, 1962
    Box/Folder 32: 5
  - South Nyanza Development Plan. Correspondence, minutes of meetings, programs, and reports
    - Volume one, (DP/5/v.1), 1966-1969
      Box/Folder 32: 6
    - Volume two, (DP/5/v.2), 1965-1966
      Box/Folder 32: 7
    - Volume three, (DP/5/v.3), 1964 (Reel 38)
      Box/Folder 32: 8
  - County Council of South Nyanza (DP/6). Minutes of meetings, 1968
    Box/Folder 33: 1
  - Ministry of Economic Planning and Development - Correspondence (DP/7). Briefing papers, correspondence, memoranda, receipts, and reports, 1965-1969
    Box/Folder 33: 2
- Governmental and Charitable Organizations Series, 1958-1969
  Architectural plans, briefing papers, brochures, charts, correspondence, financial records, maps, memoranda, minutes of meetings, notes, reports, speech, statements, and student records, largely relating to Tom Mboya's activities as Kenyan Minister for Economic Planning and Development, and as Kenyan Minister for Labor, arranged by physical form or subject in numerical sequence according to original file numbers
  - Kenya Tea Company (PAR/1). Correspondence and maps, 1967-1968
    Box/Folder 33: 3
  - Kenya Pyrethrum Board (PAR/2). Correspondence, 1962
    Box/Folder 33: 4
  - Kenya Meat Commission (PAR/3). Correspondence, minutes of meetings, notes, reports, and statements, 1958-1960
    Box/Folder 33: 5
  - Firestone Company (PAR/4). Briefing papers and charts, 1969
    Box/Folder 33: 6
  - Nairobi Casino (PAR/5). Correspondence, 1964
    Box/Folder 33: 7
  - Edelvale Trust (ET/1). Architectural plans, brochures, correspondence, financial records, memoranda, minutes of meetings, programs, speech, and reports
    - 1964-1966
      Box/Folder 33: 8. Includes typescript of a speech by Tom Mboya, 1965 October 7
    - 1967-1969 (Reel 39)
      Box/Folder 33: 9
- Local Schools Series, 1964-1969
  Architectural plans, brochures, correspondence, financial records, legal notices, minutes of meetings, newsletters, receipts, reports, speeches, student photographs, and student records, largely relating to Tom Mboya's activities as Kenyan Minister for Economic Planning and Development, arranged by school name or subject in numerical sequence according to original file numbers
  - Starehe Boys' Center (LS/1). Correspondence and newsletters, 1967-1968
    Box/Folder 34: 1
  - Kabaa Catholic Secondary School (LS/2). Correspondence, minutes of meetings, and reports, 1963-1965
    Box/Folder 34: 2
  - Pumwani Secondary School. Architectural plans, correspondence, financial records, minutes of meetings, reports, and student records
    - Volume one (LS/3/v.1)
      - 1964
        Box/Folder 34: 3
      - 1965-1967
        Box/Folder 34: 4
    - Volume two (LS/3/v.2)
      - 1967-1968
        Box/Folder 34: 5
      - 1969
        Box/Folder 34: 6
  - Mbita Secondary School (LS/4). Correspondence, financial records, legal notices, and minutes of meetings, 1966-1969 (Reel 40)
    Box/Folder 34: 7
  - Mangu High School (LS/5). Correspondence, financial records, and minutes of meetings, 1965-1969
    Box/Folder 34: 8
  - Haruma Girls' High School (LS/6). Correspondence, 1965-1968
    Box/Folder 34: 9
  - Local Schools - General Correspondence (LS/7). Correspondence, 1966-1967
    Box/Folder 35: 1
  - Local Schools and Colleges - General Correspondence. Brochures, correspondence, financial records, minutes of meetings, newsletters, receipts, reports, and speeches
    - Volume one, (LS/8/v.1), 1964-1966
      Box/Folder 35: 2
    - Volume two (LS/8/v.2)
      - 1967 (Reel 41)
        Box/Folder 35: 3
      - 1968
        Box/Folder 35: 4. Includes typescript texts of two speeches by Tom Mboya
    - Volume three, (LS/8/v.3), 1967-1969
      Box/Folder 35: 5
    - Volume four (LS/8/v.4)
      - 1968
        Box/Folder 35: 6
      - 1969
        Box/Folder 36: 1
  - Kianda College (LS/9). Correspondence, reports, and student photographs, 1964-1968
    Box/Folder 36: 2
- Institutes and Bursaries Series, 1958-1969
  Applications, articles of association, brochure, clipping, correspondence, financial records, minutes of meetings, newsletters, prospectus, receipts, reports, and student records, largely relating to Tom Mboya's activities as Kenyan Minister for Economic Planning and Development, and as Minister for Labor, arranged by name of organization or subject in numerical sequence according to original file numbers
  - Kenya Education Fund (K/1). Correspondence, memoranda, and reports, 1962-1964
    Box/Folder 36: 3
  - Kenyatta Educational Institute (K/2). Articles of association, brochure, correspondence, minutes of meetings, and reports, 1965-1966
    Box/Folder 36: 4
  - Jomo Kenyatta Foundation (K/3). Articles of association, clipping, correspondence, financial records, minutes of meetings, and reports, 1966-1968
    Box/Folder 36: 5
  - Solidarity College, Homa Bay (K/4). Correspondence, financial records, minutes of meetings, and prospectus, 1967-1969 (Reel 42)
    Box/Folder 36: 6
  - East African Literature Bureau (K/5). Correspondence, minutes of meetings, newsletters, and reports, 1966-1967
    Box/Folder 36: 7
  - Local Bursaries. Applications, correspondence, financial records, minutes of minutes, and student records, largely relating to scholarships provided to Kenyan students
    - Volume one (BS/1/v.1)
      - 1958
        Box/Folder 37: 1
      - 1959-1960
        Box/Folder 37: 2
    - Volume two, (BS/1/v.2), 1960-1962
      Box/Folder 37: 3
  - Bursaries Selection Board (BS/2). Correspondence, minutes of meetings, receipts, and student records, largely relating to scholarships provided to Kenyan students, 1962-1963
    Box/Folder 37: 4
- Representatives in Africa Series, 1956-1965
  Constitution, correspondence, news bulletins, newsletters, reports, resolutions, trade agreement, and transcript, largely relating to Tom Mboya's activities as Kenyan Minister for Economic Planning and Development, and as General Secretary of the Kenya Federation of Labor, arranged by name of country or diplomatic mission in numerical sequence according to original file numbers
  - Kenyan Embassy in Cairo (AFR/1). Correspondence and reports, 1964-1969 (Reel 43)
    Box/Folder 37: 5
  - Rhodesia. Correspondence, news bulletins, and reports
    - Volume one, (AFR/2/v.1), 1956-1962
      Box/Folder 37: 6
    - Volume two, (AFR/2/v.2), 1960-1962
      Box/Folder 37: 7
  - Nyasaland (now Malawi) (AFR/3). Correspondence and press release, 1960-1962
    Scope and Content note
    Box/Folder 38: 1. See also folder 12 below for more correspondence relating to Nyasaland/Malawi
  - Sudan. Constitution, correspondence, and reports
    - Volume one, (AFR/4/v.1)., 1956-1962
      Box/Folder 38: 2. Includes typescript of a report written by Tom Mboya, 1956 October 31
    - Volume two, (AFR/4/v.2), 1962-1964
      Box/Folder 38: 3
  - Tanganyika (now Tanzania). Correspondence, newsletters, and reports.
    Includes letters exchanged between Tom Mboya and Julius Nyerere
    - Volume one, (AFR/5/v.1), 1956-1960
      Box/Folder 38: 4
    - Volume two, (AFR/5/v.2), 1960-1962 (Reel 44)
      Box/Folder 38: 5
  - Zanzibar (now Tanzania). Correspondence
    - Volume one, (AFR/6/v.1), 1958-1960
      Box/Folder 38: 6
    - Volume two, (AFR/6/v.2), 1960-1963
      Box/Folder 38: 7
  - Congo (now Zaire) (AFR/7). Correspondence, photographs, and trade agreement, 1963-1965
    Box/Folder 38: 8. Includes a letter addressed to Jomo Kenyatta from Holden Roberto, and photographs of three journalists killed in the Congolese civil war
  - Somalia (AFR/8). Correspondence, resolutions, and transcript of radio broadcasts, 1962-1964
    Box/Folder 38: 9
  - Ethiopia (AFR/9). Correspondence, 1958-1960 (Reel 45)
    Box/Folder 38: 10
  - Senegal (AFR/10). Correspondence, 1962
    Box/Folder 38: 11
  - Malawi (AFR/11). Correspondence, 1963-1965
    Box/Folder 38: 12. See also folder 1 above for more correspondence relating to Nyasaland/Malawi
  - Madagascar (AFR/12). Correspondence, 1965
    Box/Folder 38: 13
- Government Series, 1957-1969